a cryogenically frozen human brain works
perfectly fine when thawed 18 months
later what the heck does that mean
cryogenics programs have been around
since around the
1960s where people have immersed their
bodies in liquid nitrogen in hopes of
waking up at a future date when medical
technology has advanced but it still
remains mostly Out Of Reach In fact the
bodies of people who have been
cryogenically frozen have started to
degrade this is there a combination of
just poor
and the human's body's intolerance to
being frozen I would say in every single
case of someone who is cryogenically
frozen their body they're not going to
wake up however that doesn't mean we
won't get there soon there's many
animals that can be entirely Frozen and
then wake up in the next season when
they thaw that's because they have
bioprotectants naturally in their bodies
and by borrowing these animals
techniques we're working on making
better cryoprotectants for humans and
we've done it with the brain organal
you know the tiny human brains that we
can grow in jars growing tiny fully
functional human brains is really
advancing neurological research in this
case they flooded it with the cryo
protectant and then revived it and it
suffered no damage at least no
noticeable damage while a future where
we can really just walk into a cryogenic
chamber and wake up a thousand years
later is pretty far out of reach in the
next few decades we might actually get
there